Domenico Anastasio

Web developer

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Commercial experience
- Programming client-side
- Programming server-side
- Graphic design
- Responsive design
- Windows, Linux , Mac
- Adobe suite
- WordPress
- S.E.O.
- E-commerce
- Git
- CSS preprocessor
- M.V.C.
- TDD
- AWS
- i18n & l10n
- Oauth2
- API Design

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Time management
- Goals orientated
- Creativity
- Attention to detail
- Teamworker

PERSONAL DETAILS

Domenico Anastasio

267 Green Lanes N4 2UX London

Nationality *Italian*

Mobile
+44 (0) 7932 902473
Email
nico@anastasionico.uk
Website
www.anastasionico.uk
LinkedIn
www.linkedin.com/in/anasta
sionico
GitHub
github.com/anastasionico

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A hard worker and determined person who always delivers permanently high standards, having the constant willingness to handle various responsibilities and get to know new environments and new technologies.

Able to independently organize work, even in stressful situations, thanks to the capacity obtained in the relationship with colleagues and clients during different work experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Black Diamond / Mogul | T15 Bedford Street, Covent Garden, London WC2E 9HE

PHP Developer | From February 2018

Black Diamond is recognised for expertise in producing creative campaigns and events for clients in the travel, fashion and lifestyle sectors.

Being part of the technical team, building a numerous amount of projects for our clients,

Mogul is part of Black Diamond, it is an award-winning online training and engagement platform that provides big corporations data to inform marketing and sales strategies.

Duties:

- Building and managing new and existing features in the elearning platform
- In charge of security of the web applications
- Appling S.E.O. technique for both client and e-learning platform

Imperial Commercials Ltd | Travellers Ln, Welham Green, Hatfield AL9

PHP Developer | January 2017 – February 2018

Using PHP frameworks to create web application and websites.

Exploited by the Imperial group as the owner of S&B Commercials and Orwell Trucks.

Creating external web projects for the companies partners. Duties:

- Implementing internal web applications for employees.
- S.E.O. and Design of the official websites of the companies.
- Working alongside with the marketing department to accomplish common business goals.
- Creating websites for partners all over the UK territory.

F.I.P.E. Web Design | 46 / 48 East Smithfield London E1W 1AW

Web Developer | June 2016 - September 2016 (Internship)

Realization of several projects from the research and design phases to the testing and launch stages, mainly using technologies such as JavaScript, PHP and Smarty.

Duties:

- Detecting customer needs and realization of sketches and mock-ups.
- Making layout following the responsive standards.
- Implementing of bespoke scripts.
- Controlling of the language standards, cross browser testing.

Squadra Web | Catania (CT)

Back-end Developer | August 2014 – March 2015

Working with server-side languages like PHP5 and MySql, being in charge of the realization of back-end from scratch and implementation of the database into the front-end. Duties:

- Developing back-end, advanced database driven systems including ecommerce and mantenance of websites.
- Applying oncode Seo techniques.
- Liaising with clients and ensuring that all work accomplished complies with standards required.

City Hall, Office of Public Relations | St. A. Li Battiati (CT)

Front-end Developer | December 2012 - April 2013

Creating institutional websites for companies associated with the municipality of St. A. Li Battiati contributing to the development of the PHP scripts, planning the layout with HTML and CSS and realization of the graphic items with Adobe Photoshop.

Duties:

- Designing layout from scratch.
- Writing server-side scripts and connection to databases.
- Realization of graphic and textual contents.

Maretna | Aci Bonaccorsi (CT)

Graphic designer | January 2013 – February 2013 Responsible to the pagination of the magazine using the Adobe suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign). Duties:

• Creating sketch and layout for print and online version.

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Operative systems

Microsoft Windows, Linux (CLI, GUI), Apple MacOS.

• Front end

Html5, Css3, Javascript, Jquery, Json, Ajax, Bootstrap, Sass(Smacss), Web design concept, Responsive design.

Back end

Php (CodeIgniter3, Laravel 5.4, 5.5), MySgli, testing(TDD).

• General Knowledge

Amazon Web Services (S3, RDS, EC2, IAM), S.E.O., GitHub, Adobe Photoshop. Adobe Experience Design, WordPress, Internationalization (*i18n*) & Localization (*l10n*), Oauth2, Postman, RESTful API.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

• Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Marketing | 45 Moorfields, EC2Y 9AE

March 2017

Understanding the key attributes of SEO,Best practice methodologies and strategic skills, manage online brands.

 WordPress Courses London | 22 Upper Ground, SE1 9PD November 2016

WordPress fundamentals, plugins and security, Google Analytics, Online payments

• CFP San Giovanni Apostolo | Catania (CT)

2012 – 2013

Web development, fundamental of web design.

Technical Institute "Galileo Ferraris" | Acireale (CT)

2002 – 2007 Diploma in Computer Science - Project ABACUS.

REFERENCES – Available on request.